# Rowan Torbitzky-Lane

rowan.a.tl@protonmail.com • www.brokenglass.dev • github.com/RowanTL

# Summary

To work at Garmin as a Data Engineer 2. I have experience handling SQL databasese in professional and classroom environments. At Hunter Engineering, we used Microsoft SQL to store car data. In my senior capstone class, my team used PostgreSQL (hosted on my personal server) and MongoDB to store user data.

#### Education

## Missouri University of Science and Technology

B.S. Computer Science, with a Minor in Mathematics.  $Summa\ Cum\ Laude$ 

Experience

#### **NSF REU Program**

Missouri University of Science and Technology

May 2024 - October 2024

Rolla, MO

Rolla, MO

December 2024

GPA: 3.80/4.00

- Present Research Findings Weekly at Meetings
- Experiment with LLMs and Next-Token Prediction on Genome Sequences
- Clean data with Scikit-learn and Scikit-bio

### Undergraduate Research Assistant

Center for Intelligent Infrastructure

May 2023 - October 2023

Rolla, MO

- Calculate Optical Flow with MATLAB and C++ utilizing Slurm
- Use Django to manage Web Requests
- Program User Interfaces with TypeScript
- Manipulate videos using OpenCV
- Perform Annotations for Image Segmentation Neural Networks
- Participated in Weekly Meetings discussing State of Project

#### Data Science Co-Op

Hunter Engineering Company

January 2022 - August 2022

Bridgeton, MO

- Utilize Microsoft Excel for Data Annotation
- Train Convolutional Neural Networks with YOLO and PyTorch
- Design and write APIs with FastAPI and Flask
- Containerize said APIs with Docker
- Program internal tooling with Pandas and Microsoft SQL
- Implement workflows into internal Azure DevOps Git repository
- Attend Bi-Weekly Lunch and Learns covering Full-Time Employee Responsibility

## Personal Projects

#### Self-Hosted Linux Server

January 2023 - Present

- Interact with Router Firewall
- Host Wireguard Virtual Private Network
- Manage Reverse Proxy connections with Nginx
- Point Domain Names via A Records
- Built from Components Ordered Online
- Self Host a Git Server